# **Guilherme Nunes Trofino**

# **Summary**

I'm Guilherme, a 23-year-old Brazilian student from UNICAMP, pursuing since 2022 a 3-year double degree exchange program at ENSTA Paris master's program.

I'm currently carrying out my 2nd gap year internship at Sysnav developing and validating embedded systems with magneto-inertial navigation technology.

# Experience

# Embedded Hardware Designer Intern

Sysnav

**♥** Vernon, France ■ 04/2024 – 09/2024

Experience in testing, validating, and investigating electronic systems. Skilled in electronic system design and conception, offering valuable contributions to project success.

## Retail Vendor Manager Intern

**Amazon France** 

**♥** Clichy, France ■ 09-2023 – 03/2024

July 23, 2024 [EN version]

In collaboration with a Senior Vendor Manager, I helped provide tools to optimize business performance and drive sales growth. This included an Excel macro to identify licensed selection twenth times faster, allowing deep dives in large datasets, uncovering trends, extracting customer insights, and taking action.

I also developed a comprehensive and visually appealing Dashboard in Excel, facilitating benchmarking at various levels of granularity, simplifying the identification of growth opportunities and the implementation of new strategies for the team.

### Neuroscience Research Intern

Sorbonne Université

**♥** Paris, France **■** 05/2023 – 08/2023

Developing a user-friendly simulation environment using Webots and Python, facilitating the assessment of the sensorimotor modelization of the hippocampus based on the framework proposed by Benoît Girard and Sylvain Argentieri.

## Head of Team

#### **Phoenix Robotics Team of UNICAMP**

Established in 2001 by mechatronics engineering students, the Phoenix Robotic Team had, in 2022, 83 undergraduate students from different courses designing, building, and competing with autonomous and radio-controlled robots across 12 categories.

Definition of long-term planning for the Team's departments and projects aiming for sustainable growth, resulting in a new peopledriven culture and mission setting short and medium-term targets and deadlines for the 5 area coordinators and the 12 project coordinators.

Improve Team Members' selection process, aiming for more diversity, resulting in the best inscription ratio, over 125 people from 500, and resulting in the best percentage of women among the approved, 16 from 35 people.

## Education

## MSc Engineering | Double Degree

**ENSTA Paris** 

Computer Science - Robotics

Palaiseau, France ■ 07/2022 – Ongoing

# BSc Engineering | Double Degree

UNICAMP

Control and Automation – Mechatronics

**♥** Campinas, Brazil ■ 03/2019 – Ongoing

# Languages

Portuguese: Native French: Advanced C1 English: Advanced C1

## Skills

**Programming**: C, LaTeX, MATLAB, Python and VBA

Office: Excel, PowerPoint and Word

Others: Altium Designer, Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop